# 江苏·扬州
Yangzhou, Jiangsu
# 提起扬州美食 很多人都会想起 扬州老鹅
For Yangzhou cuisine, Yangzhou goose is a popular dish for many people
# 其实来到扬州 你会发现
And you will find out here in Yangzhou
# 几乎所有的路口 都有卖老鹅的小吃车 并且人都很多
That there are carts selling geese at almost every intersection and each cart is crowded
# 卖老鹅的小推车一天会出来两次
These carts come out two times every day
# 这样有规律的活动 成了扬州一道亮丽的风景线
This pattern has been a fun view for Yangzhou
# 他们这边的老鹅 好胖啊
Their geese are so fat
# 这边除了老鹅之外 还有鹅翅
Besides the whole goose, they also sell goose wings
# 鹅胗 还有鹅头
Goose stomachs and goose heads
# 好多种
A lot of different parts
# 扬州人吃鹅呢 就是从头吃到脚 从里吃到外
People from Yangzhou eat geese from head to toe and inside out
# 你看 这边鹅胗 鹅肠 鹅肝
Have a look, there are goose stomachs, intestines and livers here
# 还有 这边一个比较特色的 鹅头 都是比较受欢迎的
And this one here is a signature, goose head, really popular
# 这是来的早 还能看到满盆的鹅血
Since we came early, we can see a whole pot of goose blood puddings too
# 全是大鹅 老鹅
They are all old geese
# 你好 老鹅 一般指的是多大的鹅
Hello, what age do you mean by old geese?
# 这个都要有一年以上的鹅才能做老鹅
Old geese need to be more than one year old
# 还有 我听说 这边做鹅还有用仔鹅做的
Also I heard we also have young geese here in Yangzhou
# 仔鹅的年龄就会小很多吧
Are they much younger?
# 仔鹅 几个月就可以了 那个没肉的
Young geese can be only a few months old. Those don’t have much meat
# 那个不管是价格 还是味道上 都会差很多
And they are much cheaper and far less tasteful
# 这个肉剁的皮开肉绽 看着都会觉得馋
Watching him cut the goose to slices really makes you hungry
# 大哥 我问一下 每次剁完鹅之后
Excuse me, may I ask what are in these two bins
# 还要浇上这两桶的东西 这两桶的东西是什么
That you pour on the geese after cutting them
# 卤水  鹅油
Master stock and goose fat
# 靠它俩调味道
The flavor comes from them
# 油是原味
# 卤水是咸的
The goose fat has the original flavor of the goose and the master stock is salty
# 拍了一个视频 老板送了我四分之一的老鹅（大概一斤）
So we shot the video and the owner gave me a quarter goose for free (about one pound)
# 尝尝这小吃车上的盐水鹅
Let’s try these salted geese from the snack cart
# 不要小看这个小吃 它可是当地的一道硬菜
Don’t underestimated this snack. It’s one of the signature dishes here
# 大菜 可以上酒席的大菜
A signature dish that can be served on fancy feasts
# 除了给的鹅之外 还给了一包的卤汤
The goose comes with a patch of master stock
# 吃的时候 把它倒进鹅里就可以了
Just pour it on the goose when you have it
# 或者有小碟子 用鹅肉蘸一蘸这个汤吃也是可以的
Or dip the goose with the stock in a small plate
# 我先不倒卤汁  先直接夹一块
I’ll hold the stock and have one slice first
# 你看 老鹅皮特别薄 肉很紧实
The skin is very thin and the meat is very firm
# 而且肉很细腻 几乎看不到肥的
The meat is also very smooth and lean
# 这么吃就会觉得很香
It already tastes so good without the stock
# 这么白口吃 就是不腥也不腻
Having it plain is already not greasy or fishy at all
# 你像我刚才那么吃 就会觉得鹅肉很香
It tastes very nice
# 但是口感上会干一些
Only a little bit dry
# 把它倒进去
Let’s pour in the stock
# 试试加了卤水和鹅油的口感
Try with the master stock and the goose fat
# 好像有点加多了
I added too much
# 这个卤汤还可以炖菜 下面条 拌饭 都是很好吃的
The master stock can also be used for stews, noodles and rice. All those are good too
# 加了卤汤的老鹅 口感上更加润滑
Goose with the master stock tastes much smoother and juicier
# 确实是可以上桌 当一道硬菜
A signature dish for fancy feast indeed
# 鹅肉放在卤水里泡一泡 味道会更好
The goose marinated in the master stock for a while tastes better
# 会显得鹅肉更加肥嫩多汁
The goose will be juicier then
# 整块的鹅肉 我觉得鹅皮是最好吃的
For a slice of goose, I like the skin the best
# 鹅皮是最肥的
It has the most fat
# 如果说 只吃鹅肉 不吃鹅皮的话
If we only eat the meat and leave the skins
# 感觉少点什么 单调了很多
It will feel a lot more blend, like missing something
# 老早就听说 卤汁可以拌饭
I also heard a lot that the stock goes great with rice
# 即使没有菜 也香的不得了
Even without other dishes, it’s really nice
# 吃完老鹅 随便逛一逛
After having the goose, l walked around casually
# 会发现 扬州好像都是这种小桥流水的感觉 特别惬意
You can see that the Yangzhou area has this style of bridges and rivers, making you really relaxed
# 背景音乐：
立山秋航 - ROMってる場合じゃないよ.
三澤康広 - つんつんけんけん.
BGM:
立山秋航 - ROMってる場合じゃないよ.
三澤康広 - つんつんけんけん.
# 关 注
# 雪 鱼 探 店
Click Subscribe!